# Leopold Haller

 ♥ Berkeley, California
 ☑ leopoldhaller@gmail.com
 ७ (510) 292-1849
 in leopoldhaller
 ♥ lcrh

#### **Summary**

I am a **research engineer** and **technical leader** with 10+ years of professional experience in software engineering, ML engineering and research. With a foundation in automated reasoning and formal verification, and recent work in generative AI and program synthesis, I am particularly interested in exploring the intersection of these fields. Seeking a challenging IC role on the cutting-edge of AI research or product development as part of a capable team.

**Key skills**: ML, RL, generative AI agents, software engineering, greenfield AI product development, automated reasoning, SAT/SMT, formal verification, theorem proving.

#### **Experience**

Cofounder & Chief Research Officer, Agentic – San Francisco, CA

June 2021 - Dec 2024

- Led **technical direction** for research team of 3, developing novel approaches to interactive training of **video** game AI for game testing.
- Pioneered novel techniques in **imitation learning and RL** to enable ML-naive game developers to train useful agents within interactive time-scales.
- Initiated a company pivot from ML to Voyager-style **LLM-based code generation** for video game AI (GDC trailer **\(\mathbb{L}\)**), owning the project from prototype through deployment.
- Developed an **open-source framework for generative software**, enact (github 🗹) to serve as the basis of our agents stack.
- Key contributor to all aspects of development, including backend infrastructure, research, UX, product, hiring.

Senior Software Engineer, Google - San Francisco, CA

May 2015 - June 2021

- Google Brain *Kernel Product Incubator* (2019): Core contributor on ML-driven video game agents, designing and implementing DAgger-style training methodology that became the foundation for **continuous live training** architecture (patent **Z**, OSS repo **Z**).
- **Area120** *Chatbase* (2017): Fine-tuned early **LLMs** (BERT) for intent detection in chat applications. My work helped secure a 9 figure enterprise deal and the first **successful exit** (\$100M internal valuation) from the Area120 incubator program. Architected high-throughput data-analytics backend for our chat telemetry platform.
- Security & Privacy (2015): Developed static code analyses for detecting privacy concerns at Google scale.

Member of Consulting Staff, Cadence Design Systems – Berkeley, CA

Dec 2012 - May 2015

• Developed SAT/SMT-based algorithms for formal verification of hardware designs, substantially reducing verification times for customers through portfolio-based approaches.

Research Intern, Microsoft – Cambridge, UK

May 2009 – Aug 2009

• Developed FPGA-based accelerator for SAT solving via novel dual-channel RAM clause encoding.

#### **Education**

University of Oxford, PhD in Computer Science, Formal Methods (dissertation ☑)	2008 - 2013
<ul> <li>14 conference &amp; journal publications</li></ul>	
Vienna University of Technology, MSc in Computational Intelligence	2006 – 2008
Johannes Kepler University Linz, BSc in Computer Science	2003 – 2006

#### **Advisorships**

Advisor, Agentic Dec 2024 – present

• Transitioned from Co-Founder / CRO into advisorship role.

Advisor, Newlife.ai May 2024 – present

• Blockchain-based project around protocolizing GenAI and agents: advising on protocol design, requirements of AI community, strategic direction.

Advisor, Standard Deviants

Mar 2023 - present

• GenAI for interative story-telling: advising on technical team composition, scriptable story-engine, image gen approaches with character and style consistency.

# **Technologies**

**Languages & Frameworks:** *Primary:* python, C++, tf, tflite, numpy; *Secondary:* jax, pandas, pytorch, lean, go, ocaml, lua, C, VHDL, etc.

Tech: gcloud, kubernetes, postgres, spanner, dremel/bigquery, grpc, protobuf

## **OSS Projects**

### enact - A framework for generative software.

github/agentic-ai 🗹

- Framework for managing execution of scaffolding programs: telemetry, serialization, record / replay.
- Example: Generic MCTS implementation for scaffolding programs (notebook)

threaded-async github/agentic-ai 🗹

• Helper library used internally at agentic to coordinate asynchronous AI-generated python code with game engines via a task system.

Falken github/google-research ☑

• Python service & C++ SDK for DAgger-style training of video game AI, built as part of a Google team.